I am a senior iOS Developer with over 20 years commercial programming experience. and over 4 years experience developing commercial iPhone/iPad applications.

Although I am very focused on iOS development, I do have significant senior management experience which is often useful in project planning, execution, team mentoring and in client-facing situations.

Skills

Tier 1 Languages/	Swift, Objective-C, Cocoa-touch, C++, C, Javascript, Web
Technologies	technologies (HTML, CSS, AJAX etc), Smalltalk
Tier 2 Languages	Java, Haskell, Ruby, CoffeeScript, C#, SQL, Shell

Experience

CONSULTING WITH SIENDA LTD, DEVON - 10/2015 - PRESENT

Firmware development in C & C++ for custom networked audio hardware on a sweat equity basis.

IOS CONTRACTING, THE LEARNING CLINIC, LONDON & EXETER - 4/2012 - 10/2015

Contracting as a senior developer and "Technical Design Authority" iOS/Objective-C. Developed award winning iOS apps for patient observation recording, tracking and escalation between nurses and doctors within hospitals.

- Recruited, led and mentored an iOS development team.
- Modernised a legacy code-base by introducing well defined protocols between components and encouraged coding standards based on industry best practice.
- Refactored the code-base behind Objective-C protocols, introducing single-responsibility and dependency injection.
- Introduced modern iOS technologies such as auto-layout, ARC, Cocoapods etc
- Dramatically simplified and removed a class of bugs from networking code by eliminating developer produced multi-threaded code, and other asynchronous code by unifying under <u>promises</u>.
- Solved long-standing client facing issues with dynamic logging, improved diagnostics and remote and on-site trouble-shooting.
- Add a visual component test harness, which decreased the coupling between components, improved developer and tester productivity and reduced defect rates.
- Migrated the code-base from SVN to Git, providing training, support and advocacy.

FOUNDING DIRECTOR, GETITMADE.COM, LONDON - 2009-2011

Full stack web development using an innovative continuation based open-source web-frame - 'Seaside' of which I was a significant open-source contributor and was selected as one of the core-maintainers. Spoke at various conferences and developed related on-line training material. Deployed using Amazon EC2, Linode and Gemstone - an object database.

CIRCUMNAVIGATION - 2005-2009

Sailed round the world aboard my own yacht - http://kikasailing.blogspot.com

HEAD OF SOFTWARE, ACTIX LTD, LONDON - 2002-2005

Started as a contractor and finally became the head of software leading a team of 60 developers. Developed components in C++; a visual state diagram editor, a 3D terrain viewer, performed aggressive optimisation on a map component. Led development of a new distributed database-backed data-processing and querying system. The technology from this project provided multiple innovations within the company including a new web-based UI allowing rapid development of novel interfaces.

TECHNICAL DIRECTOR, NYKRIS LTD, LONDON - 2000-2002

Full stack web development in Java, TLC, Javascript using Oracle and PostgreSQL. Prepared and presented proposals to clients. Worked with clients to define, refine and understand their goals for their web applications and ensured the result matched their business objectives. Hired and led a small development team.

FOUNDING DIRECTOR, TIGERTEAM SOFTWARE LTD, LONDON - 1998-2000

One of two founding directors. My presentation resulted in the seed funding which allowed us to create the company. Developed innovative web-based interfaces in DHTML.

HEAD OF SOFTWARE, DK MULTIMEDIA LTD, LONDON - 1994-1998

Started as a contractor and became the head of software with responsibility for 30 developers. Developed award winning multimedia CD-ROM software in C++. Pioneered new ways of working with 'creative staff' to help break-down the divide between technical and non-technical staff.

PROGRAMMER, SERVOTEST LTD, LONDON - 1991-1994

Developed a Windows based UI to a new range of test and control electronics in C++ and VB, including the test interface for a Formula 1 car testing rig. The software was used largely unchanged for the next 6 years within a wide range of products.

PROGRAMMER, WESSEX ELECTRONIC CONSULTANTS LTD, SOUTHAMPTON – 1989-1991 Embedded development in C. Windows development in Foxpro.

Education

BSc Electronic Engineering, University of Southampton